Sarthou family correspondence M2139
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sarthou family correspondence
c. 1911-1929
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sarthou, Henri
Sarthou, Jeanne
M2139
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Arrangement
Letters are only roughly arranged.
Biographical / Historical
Henri Sarthou was an employee of the French municipality of Shanghai in the early 1900s. He had family members living in Millau, France. He and his family members exchanged correspondence between Shanghai and Millau.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist primarily of correspondence between various Sarthou family members as well as various friends and associates. Also includes a few photographs, negatives, receipts, and other documents.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by Stanford University Libraries in 2015.
Sarthou, Henri; Sarthou, Jeanne
- Letters to Jeanne Sarthou from: Ra; Valentine; a cousin; and others (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters to Jeanne Sarthou from her brother, Henri, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters to Jeanne Sarthou from her brother, Henri, 1914-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters to Henri and Valentine Sarthou from his sister, Jeanne, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters to Henri and Valentine Sarthou from various people, 1916-1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters to Valentine Sarthou from: Lucienne, Ra; Henri and various others, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters to Henri Sarthou from various people (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters from Henri Sarthou to various people, including to his mother (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters between Henri Sarthou and Adele; from Henri to Eugene; Bon voyage telegram to Eugene and Adele (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters from J. Tapenaux (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Used envelopes dis-attached from letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Typescript documents and receipts (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fosse septique Municipalite Francaise (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 3 photographs - unidentified (Box 1, Folder 13)